Guide to the Photographer File circa 1882-2017, undated PR 50
New-York Historical Society
- Mikhailovich, Alexander
  - 1 double-sided photomechanical print of the Flatiron Building, hand-colored, 11 x 14 in. 1 color photograph, 16 x 20 in., of Times Square. 2 silver gelatin prints, 16 x 20 in. of New York street scenes. 2 photographic reproduction posters, 16 x 20 in., of the Manhattan skyline and an aerial view of midtown Manhattan., 1985-1993 (Offsite-box 8)
- Moser, Lida (1920-2014)
  - Leonard Bernstein and James Levine, 1987 (Offsite-box 4)
- Nappi, Peter
  - 10 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in. of landscapes and buildings; most depict rural scenes and ruins. All are unidentified., 1989 (Offsite-box 4)
- Newey, Simon Robert (Bob) (1959-2013)
  - "Central Park, NYC: Gay Pride Day" and "Roller Ryna", undated (Offsite-box 4)
    2 black and white photos, each roughly 11 x 14 inch". Transferred from the N-YHS museum to the library, November 2019.
- Nooney, Dinanda
  - 20 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., primarily rooftop views of the West Side Highway and the Hudson River; includes a snow view., 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4)
- Plasse, Jon
  - 3 gelatin silver photographs, 20 x24 in., from his series"Stadium Memories." Images document Yankee Stadium, showing the field and stands, the stadium exterior and elevated train station, and a mural with famous ballplayers and graffiti., [ca. 2006] (Offsite-box 10)
- Price, Clayton
  - 9 color inkjet prints of 21st century subway tunnel construction: "7 Line Tunnel inspection," "2nd Avenue Tunnel," "Workers Travel UnderGrand Central Station," "2nd Avenue Tunnel Area," "Boring Machine," "7 Line 11th Avenue Station Construction," "7 Line Extension," "Under Grand Central Metro North Station," "MTA Tunnel Drilling Rig", [2007-2016] (Offsite-box 9)
  - 7 color and black-and-white inkjet prints of Gowanus Canal, Brooklyn, New York [1 folder], 1973-2016 (Offsite-box 5)
    Titles taken from print versos. [Bracketed] descriptions drawn from photographer's notes of March 13, 2019.
    1. "First Photograph at Gowanus Canal - from Union Street Bridge," 1973. [View looking north from Union Street Bridge, with T. E. Conklin Brass & Copper painted sign at right.]
    2. "Gowanus Canal - Union Street Bridge," 2014. [Same view as #1, but with construction improvements. Conklin sign and "junk writing" on the building.]
    3. "Gowanus Overview," 2013. [Taken from roof of building at 3rd Street and 3rd Avenue; view includes industrial sites, F train overpass, and Statue of Liberty.]
    4. "Gowanus Asphalt Plant," 2013.
    5. "Gowanus Canal - Sewer Overflow Pipes," 2013.
    6. "HOMELESS," 2016. [Taken during the demolition of 18 coal silos from the early 19th century.]
    7. "Gowanus Barge Parking," 2011.
    All photographs except #5 and #6 were purchased from Clayton Price, 2019; #5 and 6 (Gowanus canal sewer overflow pipes and Homeless) were concurrent gifts from Price. (Accession no. PPAC.2019.022)
- Reves-Biro, Emery (1895-1975)
  - 3 color transparencies, 8 x 10 in., 3 gelatin silver portraits, 11 x 14 in. of Biro (self portrait), Charles Dana Gibson, and Paul Lukas(?). 1 tear sheet advertisement, and 2 black and white negatives, 8 x 10 in. of unidentified women. (2 folders), undated (Offsite-box 3)
- Robertson, Orville (1959-)
  - 3 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., of New York street scenes, particularly advertisements and signs. Titled, signed and dated by the photographer., 1985-1993 (Offsite-box 4)
- Rosen, Laura
  - 1 cibachrome color prints and 5 silver gelatin prints, all 11 x 14 in., all views of or from NYC rooftops, printed for the 2001 N-YHS "Rooftops" exhibition. Views include The Yale Truck billboard and roof gardens with people sunbathing., 1980 (Offsite-box 4)
  - 1 cibachrome color print and 1 silver gelatin prints, both 16 x 20 in., printed for the 2001 N-YHS "Rooftops" exhibition. Photos show joggers on the roof of the McGraw Hill building, and the roof of the AT&T building, with a view of the World Trade Center., 1980-1982 (Offsite-box 6)
- Rosenberg, Fred
  - 15 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., of Manhattan residents and street scenes at night, from the photographer's series "Night Gallery"., [1975] (Offsite-box 4)
- Rosenblum, Walter (1919-2006)
  - Block Party, Pitt Street, New York (4 gelatin silver photographs), 1940 (Offsite-box 4)
- Rothschild, Amalie
  - Grateful Dead Concert at the Fillmore East (3 photos), 1970 January (Offsite-box 4)
- Rudnick, James
  - 3 color prints, 11 x 14, of the Statue of Liberty renovation and cleaning. Prints made by the photographer in 2004 from his negatives. All are signed by the photographer., 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 4)
- Russell, Marie Louise
  - 54 gelatin silver prints of New York City, various sizes, including industrial sites and harbor scenes -- unusual subject matter for a woman photographer of this era (2 folders)., [1920's-1930's] (Offsite-box 2)
- Sacks, Arthur
  - 10 gelatin silver prints, 16 x 15 in., of the 72nd Street train yards in Manhattan. (3 folders), [1974-1975] (Offsite-box 6)
- Saville, Lynn (1950-)
  - 1 color photograph, 20 x 24" archival pigment print. "Grand Central, Western Facade." Edition 1 of 6. Signed, titled, dated verso in ink., 2017 (Offsite-box 11)
- Savini, Federico
  - 3 color prints of the Hua Mei Bird Garden in Chinatown, including views of birds and bird cages, exhibited in the 2003 N-YHS exhibition "Petropolis.", 1999 (Offsite-box 6)
- Schiffman, Richard (1952-)
  - 2 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., one of First Calvary Cemetery in Long Island City, Queens, with the Manhattan skyline in the background, and one of the Manhattan skyline from the Queens riverfront., 1983, 1985 (Offsite-box 4)
- Sheer, Marcia (1916-1989)
  - 2 cyanotypes and 3 sepia toned gelatin silver prints, 9 x 11 1/2 in. Park views, signed and labeled on verso in pencil., undated (Offsite-box 6)
- Squillante, Joseph
  - Kaaterskill Falls [Hudson River Portfolio], 2000 (Offsite-box 6)
  - L'il Red Lightouse from Sloop Clearwater [Hudson River Portfolio], 2000 (Offsite-box 6)
  - Sunnyside, Home of Washington Irving [Hudson River Portfolio][color print] (Offsite-box 6)
  - View from the World Trade Center, 1985, printed 2006 (Offsite-box 6)
- Stein, Harvey
  - "Man Wearing Bow Tie, Coney Island", 1970 (Offsite-box 4)
    1 gelatin silver print, 11 x 14 in. Titled and signed by Stein, 2011. Purchased from the photographer, June 20152.
- Stroh, Eve (1917-)
  - 12 modern gelatin silver prints, 8 x 10 in., from negatives taken in the 1960s of the Essex Street market preparing for the festival of Sukkot, the demolition of the 8th Regiment Armory on 94th Street, the demolition of Pennsylvania Station, and a few views of the 1964-1965 New York World's Fair. (All were printed by Wayne Goldstein in 1983)., [1960-1969] (Offsite-box 2)
- Strong, Joan Vitale
  - 2 color photographs, 11 x 14 in., portraits of Nelson Mandela taken during his 1990 trip to New York. (Offsite-box 4)
- Supraner, Leon (1925-)
  - 23 gelatin silver prints: 1 - 8 x 10 in., 7 - 11 x 14 in., 15 - 20 x 24 in. Structurally focused views of Manhattan architecture. One is an unattributed (self?) portrait of Supraner., [1970-1981] (Offsite-box 9)
- Svennevik, Donna
  - 2 color photographs, one 8 x 10 in. and one 11 x 14 in., of New York street scenes, with green and blue stripes painted on pavement by artist Eric Arctander., [1970-1989] (Offsite-box 4)
- Tress, Arthur (1940-)
  - Four black and white, 8x11 inch photos taken in Pelham Bay Park, undated (Offsite-box 2)
    Gift, Elizabeth Barlow Rogers, 2021. Added to finding aid, June 2021.
- Underwood & Underwood (est. 1882)
  - 22 gelatin silver prints, 4 x 5 inches and smaller. Unidentified New York street scenes., [1882-1900] (Offsite-box 2)
- Vauclair, Gilles
  - 20 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., of New York street scenes and structures, including the Manhattan Bridge from below, Wall Street, the Pan Am Building and Grand Central Terminal, the World Trade Center, and the Woolworth Building. Also includes a view of 42nd Street and Lexington Avenue in a snow storm. Two prints from Queens: a view of snow-covered elevated train tracks north from the Astoria Boulevard station to the Ditmars Boulevard terminal in Queens and of the number 7 subway train descending into the Queensboro Plaza station, Swingline Staplers sign visible in the distance., 1980-1989 (Offsite-box 4)
- Van Loen, Alfred (attributed)
  - [Young boy embracing Alice in Wonderland sculpture in Central Park], 1968 (Offsite-box 10)
    General Note
    Includes sketch and inscription on back
- Von Dem Bussche, Wolf
  - 10 gelatin silver prints, 16 x 20 in. Views of New York, including the World Trade Center, Washington Square, the Flatiron Building, and Foley Square housed in a custom-made metal box. Entitled "N.Y., N.Y. Ten Photographs.", 1967-1976 (Offsite-box 7)
- Wampler, Damien
  - Darfur in Brooklyn [Coney Island Avenue], circa 2010 (Offsite-box 10)
- Waters, Ray
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in., mounted, of Bernard M. Baruch sitting on his favorite Central Park Bench, as a boy reads the plaque dedicating the bench to Baruch. A "Daily News" clipping of the published photograph is mounted to the verso., 1958 (Offsite-box 6)
- Wilcox, Richard (1945-), 1999
  - "Flatiron Building", 1999 (Offsite-box 13)
    Inkjet print/digital photograph, matted. Gift, Marilyn Symmes, April 2022. Credit line: "Marilyn F. Symmes"
  - "Municipal Building, No. 1", 1999 (Offsite-box 13)
- Wright, Paula
  - 14 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in. and smaller. Portraits of children, pets, Albert Einstein (1946), and a self portrait. Other photographs include cows moving across the Hungarian countryside, Mexican men gathered on a stoop, and elderly farmer and his wife in the Adirondack Mountains. All are signed or initialed., 1940-1969 (Offsite-box 4)
  - 2 gelatin silver prints, 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in., mounted, of New York street life. One portrays children playing street games in Harlem; the other portrays a barefoot man sleeping on a bench, covered with a newspaper with World War II headlines. Both are signed and dated by the photographer., 1944 (Offsite-box 6)
  - 15 color slides, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in., of the 1964-1965 New York World's Fair including lights, people, structures and fountains. (Offsite-box 2)
- Wyatt, John
  - 3 black and white prints of tattoo artist Thom de Vita and his clients at his studio at 326 East 4th Street., 1976 (Offsite-box 6)
- Yankus, Marc
  - San Remo (pigment print), 2008 (Offsite-box 10)
  - PK [snowy rooftops] (pigment print), 2011 (Offsite-box 10)
- Zimbel, George (1929-)
  - "A Day in Bedford Stuyvesant Brooklyn, 1968" (12 photos) (Offsite-box 4)
- Unidentified
  - Images include architectural ornaments, birds on tree, motorcycles, beach with view of Statue of Liberty, trash on beach, elevated subway station with rooftops, mowing lawn in Central Park, aerial view of parade, and others (Offsite-box 10)
  - Images include World Trade Center; Flushing, Queens; cable cars to Roosevelt Island; boats on the East River; High Bridge; South Street Seaport Museum; New York Botanical Garden; excavation site; aerial view of Manhattan; jockey in horse race; Bi-centennial Tall Ships Parade?; street scene with Hispanics; trash; Central Park; water tanks; beach scenes; and others, circa 1970's - 1990's (Offsite-box 10)